<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kiln:root xmlns:i18n="http://apache.org/cocoon/i18n/2.1"
           xmlns:kiln="http://www.kcl.ac.uk/artshums/depts/ddh/kiln/ns/1.0"
           xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
           xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform">

  <kiln:parent>
    <xi:include href="base.xml" />
  </kiln:parent>

  <kiln:child>
    <kiln:block name="title">
      <i18n:text>Fiscus</i18n:text>
    </kiln:block>

    <kiln:block name="page-header">
      <div class="row">
        <div class="large-12 columns text-center">
          <h1 id="fiscal_estate">Fiscal Estate in Medieval Italy: Continuity and Change <br/>(9th – 12th centuries)</h1>
        </div>
      </div>
    </kiln:block>

    <kiln:block name="content-section">
      <main>
        <div class="row">
          <div id="home-text" class="small-8 large-centered columns">
            <a href="documents/"><img id="logo" src="{$kiln:assets-path}/images/logo.png" alt="Logo Fiscus: Sella plicatilis" /></a>
            <p>The aim of the project is to study the economic and patrimonial dimension of public powers in the High Middle Ages, by exploring the relations between religious and political institutions and the structures of the Kingdom of Italy in the post-Carolingian age. In particular, the project intends to study the relation between the status of the fiscal estates endowed and received over the course of the 10th and 11th centuries, and the survival of a public dimension associated with the ownership of such estates. Our project aims to broaden the investigation into the economic foundations of public powers by adopting a long-term perspective – the 9th-12th centuries – and taking the whole Italian peninsula into account, focusing on three key questions: the problem of the documentary evidence for the study of fiscal estates; the history of the fiscal patrimony and of its development in the 11th and 12th centuries; the legacy of early medieval fiscal estates in the 11th and 12th centuries.</p>
            <p>Obiettivo del progetto è studiare la dimensione economica e patrimoniale del potere pubblico nei secoli centrali del Medioevo, indagando in tal senso le relazioni tra gli enti religiosi e civili e le strutture del regno in età postcarolingia. In particolare si intende studiare il rapporto fra lo statuto dei beni fiscali, dati e ricevuti nel corso dei secoli X e XI, e la sopravvivenza di una dimensione pubblica legata al possesso di quei beni. Il nostro progetto si propone di allargare l’indagine sulle basi economiche del potere pubblico in una prospettiva di lungo periodo – dal IX al XII secolo – e su contesti geografici che comprendano l’intera penisola italiana, soffermandosi su tre questioni: le basi documentarie per lo studio dei beni fiscali; il destino del patrimonio fiscale e la sua evoluzione nei secoli XI e XII; le eredità lasciate ai secoli XI e XII dai beni fiscali altomedievali.</p></div>
          <div id="credits" class="small-8 large-centered columns">
            <p>Powered by <a href="http://kcl-ddh.github.io/kiln/">Kiln</a>/<a href="https://github.com/EpiDoc/EFES/wiki">EFES</a>. Theme by <a href="http://foundation.zurb.com/">Foundation</a>.</p>
            <p><a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/"><img alt="CC BY-SA" style="padding-left:0.9em; padding-right:1.2em; padding-bottom:0.2em" src="https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/4.0/80x15.png" /></a></p>
          </div>
        </div>
      </main>
    </kiln:block>
  </kiln:child>
</kiln:root>
